# **STEVEN OWENS**

✓ sd.owens@outlook.com
 ✓ 360.908.9855
 ✓ github.com/sd-owens
 PORTFOLIO https://sd-owens.herokuapp.com

### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Upcoming Computer Science graduate at Oregon State University ready to enter the civilian workforce as a software engineer following completion of my military service. I hold a previous bachelor's degree in business and over 20 years of progressive experience as a program manager in one of most technically demanding fields in the US. Armed Forces, the Navy's Nuclear Propulsion program. I hold an active SECRET clearance and am available for employment in Sept. 2020.

TECHNICAL SKILLS					
C / C++	Express	MySQL	Concurrency	Git / VCS	Team Leadership
Python	NodeJS	Bootstrap4	OpenMP	GCloud / Heroku	Team Development
Java	EJS	Django	CUDA	Microsoft TFS	Requirement Analysis
HTML, CSS	JavaScript	Linux	OpenCL	Asana / Trello	Release Testing
EDUCATION   CERTIFICATIONS					

BS, COMPUTER SCIENCE | Oregon State University | Corvallis, OR

Grad 12/2020

Cumulative GPA: 3.96

BS, OPERATIONS AND PROJECT MANAGEMENT | Southern New Hampshire University | Manchester, NH

Summa Cum Laude

PROFESSIONAL PROJECT MANAGER (PMP), Project Management Institute. SAFE FOR TEAMS, CERTIFIED SAFE PRACTITIONER (SP), Scaled Agile, Inc.

Active I Issued 05/2019

Active I Issued 10/2018

## **PROJECTS**

#### LOW LEVEL IO IN ASSEMBLY LANGUAGE

(HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/SD-OWENS/LOWLEVELWIN32API)

Implemented hardware level input and output operations using Win32API macros in Microsoft Assembly language (MASM). Allows fastest performance of arithmetic calculations at one abstraction above the machine language.

#### RowForReveille.com

(HTTPS://SD-OWENS-ROW4REVEILLE.HEROKUAPP.COM)

• Designed and implemented a mobile-first dynamic website in support of charity fundraiser for Project Reveille. Utilized NodeJS and Express as back-end. Front-end in embedded JavaScript and BootStrap4. Deployed via Heroku.

#### **AUTOMATED FOOD DELIVERY APPLICATION**

(HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/SD-OWENS/AUTOMATEDFOODDELIVERY)

Led a team of 5 in the user experience and interface design (UX/UI) for an automated food delivery application. Utilized PRICPE design process. Prototype created on Apple iOS using the Figma Interface Design Tool.

## SOUL EXCHANGE AUCTION PLATFORM

(HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/SD-OWENS/SOUL EXCHANGE)

 Collaborated to build a full featured auction website for goods or services. Built on NodeJS with Express as the backend with full CRUD functionality (SQL). Front-end in embedded JavaScript and BootStrap4. Deployed via Heroku.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## PROGRAM MANAGER / TESTING TEAM LEAD, US NAVY

12/2016 TO PRESENT

- Supervise a team of six subject matter experts ensuring maximum up-time, software development, software release testing, and version control of a \$8 million submarine nuclear reactor plant simulator for over 1200 end-users in the pacific northwest. Managed bug tracking and feature requests using git and Microsoft Team Foundation Server.
- Manage simulator day to day operations, testing, patching, and quality control sustaining an unmatched 150% utilization rate of asset with 0% unplanned downtime across the entire program domain.
- Implemented agile methodologies to prioritize product backlogs reducing iteration duration between feature and enhancement deployments by over 50%. Work directly with customers for product feedback and feature requests.

# WEB DEVELOPER / FULL STACK ENGINEER, SELF-EMPLOYED

9/2019 TO 2/2020

- Designed and managed a full stack, dynamic, mobile-first web application for Row4Reveille, an annual local fundraising event presented by Kitsap CrossFit. Row4Reveille is a major sponsored fundraising event for The Reveille Project, a national 501(c)(3) non-profit organization.
- Implemented using NodeJS, Express, EJS, and Bootstrap4. Deployed via Heroku as a Platform as a Service (PaaS).
- Collaborated with customer to design a solution to meet baseline customer requirements with scalability to meet future enhancements and feature requests.

# STEVEN OWENS

✓ sd.owens@outlook.com
 ✓ 360.908.9855
 ✓ linkedin.com/sd-owens
 ✓ github.com/sd-owens
 PORTFOLIO https://sd-owens.herokuapp.com

# WORK EXPERIENCE (CONT'D)

### **ENGINEERING PROGRAM MANAGER, US NAVY**

09/2010 TO 12/2016

- Supervised five cross-functional teams (7-14 members per team) consisting of 60+ total team members responsible
  for ensuring maximum readiness for overseas assignment of a naval nuclear submarine reactor plant and associated
  propulsion support equipment. Ensured adherence to all technical requirements in dynamic, high stress environment.
- Managed implementation and end-user testing of software solution for electronic documentation of training and qualification programs for over 320 end-users. Maximized customer success by generating best practices and lessons learned for future implementation on similar platforms in pacific northwest.
- Managed project scope, schedule, and budget ensuring maximum sustainability in extended overseas assignments.
   Established "best-of-the-best" culture for training and readiness, ensured long-term organizational success through effective team development and cross-training, resulted in recognition as #1 of 14 peer managers in region.

## PROGRAM MANAGER / CONSULTANT, US NAVY

4/2009 TO 8/2010

- Managed overall overseas assignment planning, requirement generation, team development, regulatory oversight, and certification for 3 nuclear fast attack submarines consisting of over 400+ employees.
- Acted as part of a team of senior nuclear trained professionals responsible for evaluating all aspects of reactor safety, operations, maintenance, equipment, material condition, training and proficiency.
- Set standards and metrics to evaluate nuclear operator performance and training programs ensured full operational capabilities of assigned organizations.

#### QUALITY ASSURANCE SUPERVISOR / INSPECTOR, US NAVY

4/2000 TO PRESENT

- Responsible for training of submarine force supervisory personnel on the information, references, and procedures necessary to manage and administer the Submarine Force Quality Assurance Program.
- Coordinates and maintains quality assurance material storage surveillances and schedules; conducts SUBSAFE
  quality assurance surveillances; documents field changes; verifies and develops procedural documentation, conducts
  quality assurance safety surveillances; documents special projects alternations (SPALT); and reviews technical work
  packages.
- Submits quality discrepancy reports; conducts quality assurance program inspections; prepares and submits re-entry
  control forms; prepares control work packages; submits departure form specifications packages; conducts acceptance
  inspections on components; reviews and updates divisional logs and records; compiles equipment performance data;
  and uses special purpose electronic test equipment.